[
    {
        "question": "What is ReactJS?",
        "optionA": "Server side framework",
        "optionB": "User-interface framework",
        "optionC": "Both A and B",
        "optionD": "None of the Above",
        "answer": "User-interface framework",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: React is the view Part of MVC Architechture."
    },

    {
        "question": "In React, what is used to change the state of a component?",
        "optionA": "modifyState",
        "optionB": "updateState",
        "optionC": "setState",
        "optionD": "changeState",
        "answer": "setState",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: This function is used to update the state of a React component and trigger a re-render."
    },

    {
        "question": "What is the virtual DOM used for in React?",
        "optionA": "Handling User Authentication",
        "optionB": " Server-Side Rendering",
        "optionC": "Form Validation",
        "optionD": " Optimization",
        "answer": " Optimization",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: It helps to improve the performance of React applications by minimizing DOM updates."
    },

    {
        "question": "In React, what is used to pass data from a parent component to a child component?",
        "optionA": "Data Propagation",
        "optionB": "Data Transfer",
        "optionC": "Data Relay",
        "optionD": "Props",
        "answer": "Props",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: Transmit data from one component to another in a unidirectional flow."
    },

    {
        "question": "What lifecycle method is called after a component is rendered for the first time",
        "optionA": "renderComplete",
        "optionB": "componentDidUpdate",
        "optionC": "componentDidMount",
        "optionD": "componentWillMount",
        "answer": "componentDidMount",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: Used for data fetching and setting up subscriptions in a React component."
    },

    {
        "question": "What tool is used to bundle and package a React application for production?",
        "optionA": "Reactify",
        "optionB": "Webpack",
        "optionC": "Rollup",
        "optionD": "Grunt",
        "answer": "Webpack",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: Popular build tool that can bundle, minify, and optimize your React application for deployment."
    },

    {
        "question": "What JSX feature allows embedding expressions within curly braces?",
        "optionA": "Interpolation",
        "optionB": "Injection",
        "optionC": "Embedding",
        "optionD": "CurlyBracing",
        "answer": "Interpolation",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: This is how dynamic values are added to JSX."
    },

    {
        "question": "Component primarily responsible for rendering UI elements and does not manage state?",
        "optionA": "Functional component",
        "optionB": "Class component",
        "optionC": "Container component",
        "optionD": "Higher-Order Component (HOC)",
        "answer": "Functional component",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: These components are stateless."
    },

    {
        "question": "In one-way binding, where is the source of truth for the data?",
        "optionA": "Child components",
        "optionB": "Parent components",
        "optionC": "External API",
        "optionD": "Redux store",
        "answer": "Parent components",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: In one-way binding, data flows from a central location to child components."
    },

    {
        "question": "How many elements can a valid react component return?",
        "optionA": "No elements",
        "optionB": "1 Element",
        "optionC": "More than 1 element",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer": "1 Element",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: The return value of a component's render method can only consist of a single root element. "
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is method is not a part of ReactDOM?",
        "optionA": "ReactDOM.hydrate()",
        "optionB": "ReactDOM.destroy()",
        "optionC": "ReactDOM.createPortal()",
        "optionD": "All of the above",
        "answer": "ReactDOM.destroy()",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: ReactDOM is primarily responsible for rendering and updating React components in the DOM. "
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
        "optionA": "Original DOM",
        "optionB": "Virtual DOM",
        "optionC": "Both A and B.",
        "optionD": "Props",
        "answer": "Virtual DOM",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: This involves creating a lightweight, in-memory representation of the actual DOM. "
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a must API for every React.js component?",
        "optionA": "SetinitialComponent",
        "optionB": "renderComponent",
        "optionC": "render",
        "optionD": "All of the above",
        "answer": "renderComponent",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: It is a fundamental part of every React component's lifecycle."
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
        "optionA": "Create",
        "optionB": "Inherits",
        "optionC": "This",
        "optionD": "Extends",
        "answer": "Extends",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: In modern JavaScript, class inheritance is typically implemented using this keyword."
    },

    {
        "question": "How many ways of defining your variables in ES6?",
        "optionA": "1",
        "optionB": "3",
        "optionC": "4",
        "optionD": "5",
        "answer": "3",
        "hintsMessage": "Hint: ES6 introduced multiple ways to declare variables in JavaScript."
    }
]